(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T23:25:12.265154",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Welcome to Chromatic Future.
身も心も...
Body and soul...
この手で make you mine
With these hands, I'll make you mine.
Oh baby, I need you, I need you ずっと
Oh baby, I need you, I need you forever.
君を見るたび 上書きされてく欲望に
Every time I look at you, in desires that get overwritten,
重なる Eyes, Eyes, Eyes
Meeting Eyes, Eyes, Eyes
胸を刺す Your Smile, Smile, Smile
Piercing my heart, Your Smile, Smile, Smile
ねえ その姿 かたち
Hey, that appearance, that form
すべてが 拍車かけてく
Everything spurs it on.
恋から 愛、愛、愛
From romance to Love, Love, Love
毎秒 眩しくなってく
Becoming brighter every second
手を伸ばせば もう届く距離
A distance reachable if I stretch my hand
100% 試したい
I want to test 100%
穏やかに 恋したい
I want to fall in love peacefully
どんなシーンも 私に見せて
Show me every single scene
このまま Stay by my side
Stay by my side just like this
どこにも行かないで
Don't go anywhere
Ah 100% 純粋な愛だから
Ah, because it's 100% pure love
止められない感情
An unstoppable feeling
その腕で 抱きしめてよ
Hold me in those arms of yours
ずっと ここからさ
Forever from right here
もっと 近くで
Closer and closer
見つめ合いたい
I want to gaze into your eyes
余るほどの モテあます感情 掻き鳴らせ
Strumming these unmanageable overflowing emotions
Hey, tell me, what's wrong with me
何にも言えない 僕らしさ
Being unable to say anything, so like me
君の全部 知りたい
I want to know everything about you
I do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now
最初は 声かけるだけでよかった
At first, just talking to you was enough
だけど 次第に我がままになった
But gradually, I became selfish
誰かに笑いかけ その仕草に苛立ち
Irritated by you smiling at someone else,
隠せない自分に気づいた
I realized I couldn't hide my feelings
ひとりじめしたい
I want to have you all to myself
いっそ 鎖につないで
Rather, chain me up
二人きりの部屋 至近距離
In a room with just the two of us, at close range
衝動 発現化したい
I want to express this impulse
声きいて 眠りたい
I want to fall asleep listening to your voice
君の吐息 感じさせて
Let me feel your breath
永遠に Stay by my side
Forever, Stay by my side
どこにも渡さない
I won't give you away to anyone
Ah 100% 私だけに依存してね
Ah, depend 100% on me alone, okay?
いいでしょう
Is that alright?
黒く染まる愛憎 丸ごと受け止めてよ
Accept this blackened love and hate entirely
私なしじゃ
Without me,
たとえ息ができない いかないでよ
even if you can't breathe, don't go away
あふれる衝動
An overflowing impulse
あともどりできない 絶対
There's absolutely no turning back
Hey, tell me, what's wrong with me
何にも言えない 僕らしさ
Being unable to say anything, so like me
君の全部 知りたい
I want to know everything about you
I do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now
目を閉じたら とめどない愛が
When I close my eyes, an endless love...
あふれて
...overflows
私の歌声だけ
Only my singing voice
Forever stay by my side
二度と離れないで
Never leave me again
Ah 100% 純粋な愛
Ah, 100% pure love
だから Ready
So, ready?
止められない感情
Unstoppable feelings
そこで抱きしめてよ
Hold them close right there
遠くからじゃなく
Not from afar,
ずっともっと近くで
but much, much closer,
認め合いたい
I want us to understand each other.
Abracadabra show time
Abracadabra, showtime!
Tell me what's wrong with me
何も問題ない振り出し
Back to square one with no problems
Why away? 意味の全部知りたい
Why away? I want to know all the meaning
I do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now!
Oh baby, I need you, I need you ずっと
Oh baby, I need you, I need you forever
Mikir kalau cuma
Think about it, if you only
Pengen menang, ya, jangan ngacak-ngacak!
want to win, don't mess things up!
Are you online?
Mau chat-an sama new name
Want to chat with a new name?
Naik sari di 15 mins?
Rising up in 15 mins?
Nih, buka mata, harusnya tahu
Hey, open your eyes, you should know
Siapa...
Who it is...
Just stay scanning!
Ada yang beda, standby, ya
Something's different, standby now
Mulai bosan, jujur, makin-makin aja, ya
Honestly starting to get bored, it's getting too much
Namun bahwasannya, bersenang-senang, ini makin asyik, ya!
But having fun is getting even more exciting!
Lakukan itu, coba tengok
Do that, take a look
Mana yang lebih di antara 20
Which one is better among the 20
Aku tak pernah ragu, nah, kaya gini
I never doubt, yeah, like this
Rasanya tak cukup hanya...
It feels like it's not enough just to...
Day by day, coba cari
Day by day, try to find it
Minta apa saja, tentu bisa saja
Ask for anything, of course it's possible
Tapi jangan pernah...
But don't you ever...
Victory to the world, yay!
Jadi, tak usah ragu, ini pasti
So, no need to hesitate, this is definitely it
Lihat, demi... yuk, kemari... datanglah ke sini!
Look, for the sake of... come here... come over here!
Waktu lalu, tak ada yang tahu
Back then, nobody knew
Setiap kali, langkah yang baru
Every time, a new step forward
Kalau suka, senang, pasti terasa
If you like it and enjoy it, you'll surely feel it
Tinggi di atas awan
High above the clouds
Tapi aku yang buat makin bersinar
But I'm the one making it shine brighter
Harus bisa leluasa
Must be able to move freely
Asyik kan, 1 2 3
Isn't it fun, 1 2 3
Singing trip to trip
Hingga tak ada lagi yang sembunyi
Until nobody is hiding anymore
Tak kan pernah berhenti
Will never stop
Naik, fight, terus berjalan
Rise up, fight, keep moving forward
Semua akan baik-baik saja
Everything is going to be alright
Biar aku yang bawa kamu ke sana
Let me take you over there
Victory to the world, yay!
Tolong menari bersama di sini
Please dance together here
Ini hari yang paling tercinta
This is the most beloved day
Kini saatnya kita bersinar
Now is our time to shine
Oi! Oi! Oi! Oi!
Ayo, nyanyi bersama!
Come on, sing together!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
BPM makin cepat
BPM is getting faster
Here I am, tak pernah ragu
Here I am, never hesitating
Day by day, mari kita berdansa
Day by day, let's dance together
Momen ini tak kan terlupakan
This moment will never be forgotten
Victory to the world, yay!
Setinggi langit, cahaya yang indah
As high as the sky, beautiful light
Kemenangan milik kita
Victory belongs to us
Ikuti irama ini!
Follow this rhythm!
Saat dunia tak berjalan semestinya
When the world doesn't turn as it should,
Mungkin sudah saatnya
Maybe it's about time
Kau coba lepaskan saja
You try to just let go.
Tak perlu tanya mengapa lagi
No need to ask why anymore.
Jika memang...
If indeed...
Jawaban tak kau dapatkan
...you don't get an answer,
Jangan tangisi, cobalah lalui teka-tekinya
don't cry over it, try to get through its riddle.
Relakanlah...
Let it go...
Karena pada akhirnya...
...because in the end...
Kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
...you are stronger than you think.
Dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just let it be, oh just let it be.
Jalanin saja
Just live through it.
Dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just let it be, oh just let it be.
Jalanin saja
Just live through it.
Mulai lagi...
Here we go again...
Walau kadang mati rasa
Even if sometimes feeling numb,
Bahkan hingga tak berdaya
even to the point of feeling helpless,
Dan usahamu terasa sia-sia
and your efforts feel like they're in vain.
Jika memang, memang jawaban tak kau dapatkan
If indeed, indeed you don't get an answer,
Jangan tangisi, cobalah lalui teka-tekinya
don't cry over it, try to get through its riddle.
Relakanlah...
Let it go...
Karena pada akhirnya...
...because in the end...
Kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
...you are stronger than you think.
Lepas semua kendali
Let go of all control.
Tancap gas sambil berlari
Step on the gas while running.
Terima dan sudahi...
Accept it and end it...
Jika memang...
...if indeed...
Jawaban tak kau dapatkan
...you don't get an answer,
Jangan tangisi, cobalah lalui teka-tekinya
don't cry over it, try to get through its riddle.
Relakanlah...
Let it go...
Karena pada akhirnya...
...because in the end...
Kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
...you are stronger than you think.
You are stronger than you think.
Dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just let it be, oh just let it be.
Jalanin saja
Just live through it.
Dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just let it be, oh just let it be.
Jalanin saja
Just live through it.
Mainkan!
Hit it!
Halo Holo Friends!
Hello, Holo Friends!
Welcome to Hololive Indonesia 3rd Anniversary Live Chromatic Future!
Wah, gila gila gila!
Wow, this is insane, insane, insane!
Makasih banyak semuanya udah pada dateng ke konser 3 tahun kita ya!
Thank you so much everyone for coming to our 3rd anniversary concert!
Wah, gak berasa banget gak sih udah 3 tahun aja?
Wow, doesn't it feel like time flew, it's already been 3 years?
Kalau gitu, kita mulai dari perkenalan diri dulu gak sih?
In that case, shouldn't we start with self-introductions first?
Mulai dari aku! Aku!
Starting with me! Me!
Eh, di belakang... Oke.
Ah, in the back... Okay.
A-a-a Mission... Start-o!
A-a-a Mission... Start!
Aku Vestia Zeta dari Hololive Indonesia Gen 3. Nice to meet you!
I'm Vestia Zeta from Hololive Indonesia Gen 3. Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you, Zeta!
Kaela Kovalskia, grinding every time, the blacksmith from Hololive ID Gen 3. I'm Kaela Kovalskia, nice to meet you all!
Nice to meet you, Kaela!
Next, next, next... Kobo! Kobo! Kobo!
Boko-boko-bokoba, Kobo Kanaeru at your service! Let me be your sun to shine your day!
Kobo batuk... Mana suaranya?!
Kobo's coughing... Let me hear your voices!
Nah, bertiga kami dari...
Now, the three of us are from...
Hololive Indonesia Gen ketiga, HoloHero!
Hololive Indonesia 3rd Generation, HoloHero!
Wah, gak nyangka juga deh, konser 3rd Anniversary Hololive ID ini akhirnya ada juga!
Wow, I really didn't expect that Hololive ID's 3rd Anniversary concert would finally happen!
Dari lagu pertama aja udah keren banget, guys!
Just from the first song, it's already so cool, guys!
Pasti semangat ya. Iya enggak sih?
You're excited, right? Isn't that so?
Lihat para si ada adrenalin rasakannya. Pengen lari aku rasanya nih.
Look, everyone feels the adrenaline rush. I feel like running!
Wait, wait, wait... Mau ke mana?
Wait, wait, wait... Where are you going?
Mau ke mana? Stop stop stop stop!
Where are you going? Stop, stop, stop, stop!
Nanti keringetan loh. Ah, Kaela gimana?
You'll get sweaty, you know! So, Kaela, how do you feel?
Aduh, seru banget! Aku enggak nyangka sih, sampe aku bisa ada di sini ya.
Oh, it's so exciting! I never expected to be standing here.
Tapi ini ngomong-ngomong konsernya masih panjang banget, jadi kalian tetap semangat ya sampai akhir!
But anyway, this concert is still long, so stay hyped until the end!
Semangat! Semangat banget!
Yeah! Stay hyped! Keep your spirits up!
Eh, tapi ngomongin konser dari tadi, emang pada tahu judul konsernya apa?
Hey, speaking of the concert, does everyone know the title of the concert?
Judul konser kita kali ini adalah Chromatic Future!
Our concert title this time is "Chromatic Future"!
Ada yang tahu enggak artinya apa? Ayo absen!
Does anyone know what it means? Come on, tell us!
Nah ini, Kobo paling tahu.
Here, Kobo knows it best.
Yang jelasin yang paling tinggi! Ya, Kaela!
Let the tallest one explain it! Yes, Kaela, go!
Gak gitu ya! Ya udah lah. Ya udah, ya udah. Nih ya guys ya...
It's not like that! Alright then. Okay, guys...
buat kalian yang belum tahu, Chromatic Future itu artinya tuh masa depan yang berwarna-warni.
for those who don't know, Chromatic Future means a colorful future.
Jadi karena hololive Indonesia kan udah 5 tahun nih, kita sama-sama dari hari 1 sampai sekarang.
Since hololive Indonesia has been around for 5 years, we've been together from Day 1 until now.
Nah, jadi tuh untuk kedepannya kita tuh juga harapannya tuh kita bisa nyiptain waktu dan memori yang berwarna-warni sama seluruh fans dari hololive Indonesia!
So going forward, we hope to create colorful time and memories together with all hololive Indonesia fans!
Iya gitu! Betul! Kaela Kovalskia! Cerdas cerdas betul betul!
That's right! Exactly! Kaela Kovalskia is so smart! Exactly!
Nah, kalian sekarang udah pada tahu kan? Karena tadi udah dijelasin sama Kaela.
So now you all know, right? Since Kaela just explained it.
Kalau gitu, konsernya kan udah mulai nih. Kalian mau ngepost soal konser ini di medsos,
Since the concert has started, if you want to post about this concert on social media,
jangan lupa hashtag #idChromaticFuture ya!
don't forget to use the hashtag #idChromaticFuture, okay?
Karena kita pengen banget lihat kalian tuh... pengen lihat semangat kalian!
Because we really want to see your excitement!
Ya, itu! Betul banget, ya enggak? Jangan typo! Jangan typo!
Yes, exactly! That's right! Don't make typos! Don't make typos!
Asik, share ke semua, oke?
Nice! Share it to everyone, okay?
Jadi... tapi jujur deh, kalian tuh pas dibilang kita bakal konser loh di Indonesia, kalian pada kaget enggak sih?
So... but honestly, were you guys surprised when you were told we'd have a concert in Indonesia?
Betul.
That's right.
Aku setuju juga. Aku merasakan empati...
I agree too. I feel empathy...
...terhadap adik saya Zeta. Iya empati iya iya.
...towards my little sister Zeta. Yes, empathy, yeah yeah.
Kalau Kaela gimana Kaela Kovalskia?
What about Kaela? Kaela Kovalskia?
Aku juga waktu itu enggak nyangka banget kayak, "Hah? Beneran? Ini really?" gitu kan. Kayak, "Loh, bisa gitu? Akhirnya, mana udah bersembilan di Indonesia pula," ya kan. Keren banget!
I couldn't believe it back then either, like, "Huh? Really? Is this real?" Like, "Woah, really? Finally, all nine of us in Indonesia!" Right? So cool!
Keren banget! Keren banget! Iya.
So cool! So cool! Yeah!
Ini kan konser pertama hololive Indonesia yang bersembilan.
This is hololive Indonesia's first concert with all nine members.
Sebenernya tuh enggak hanya ini tuh momen terbesar dan terpenting juga untuk fans hololive Indonesia, tapi seluruh dunia juga pasti bakal nonton enggak sih?
Actually, this isn't just the biggest and most important moment for hololive Indonesia fans, but people all over the world will watch it too, right?
Ya enggak? Jawab!
Right? Answer us!
Iya iya, makasih makasih semuanya. Wait, tapi tentu aja ini pencapaiannya enggak bakal cuma sampai di sini aja kan?
Yeah, thank you everyone. But wait, of course this achievement won't just stop here, right?
Jadi, next-nya mungkin kita bisa apa ya... dominating the world! Gitu, we are ready! Ready ready ready!
So next, maybe we can... dominating the world! Like that! We are ready!
Ready ready ready! Betul banget! Kaela! Zeta!
Ready, ready, ready! Absolutely! Kaela! Zeta!
Selain dari dukungan fans in this opportunity, kita juga mau mengucapkan terima kasih...
Besides fan support in this opportunity, we also want to express our gratitude...
...untuk semua sponsor yang mendukung terjadinya konser ini! Terima kasih!
...to all sponsors who supported making this concert happen! Thank you!
Makasih! Makasih semuanya!
Thank you! Thank you everyone!
Eh, tapi ngomong-ngomong di konser ini kayaknya ada yang beda enggak sih? Ela, kamu nyadar enggak? Soalnya kamu paling peka enggak sih?
By the way, doesn't something look different in this concert? Ela, did you notice? You're the most sensitive one, right?
Wets! Ya sadarlah! Kalau Kobo mah enggak bakal sadar.
Woah! Of course I noticed! Kobo wouldn't notice though.
Nih nih nih nih. Yang beda tuh kali ini tuh model kita, ini model baru nih!
Look look look! What's different this time is our 3D models. These are new models!
Ooo... Gemes banget! Lucu-lucu!
Aww, so cute! So adorable!
Lucu lucu lucu! Kameranya dekatin ke aku! Kameranya dekatin ke aku! Kalian mau lihat keimutan Kobo nih.
So cute! Zoom in on me! Camera, zoom in on me! You guys wanna see Kobo's cuteness, right?
Wait wait wait, eh sini sini sini, ini kamera diambil Kobo semua enggak sih? Ini ke Kael juga! Jangan Kobo doang, udah.
Wait, wait, hey! Is the camera capturing only Kobo? Put it on Kael too! Not just Kobo. Come on.
Nggak bisa, enggak bisa! Kamera tinggal Kobo lagi! Imut kan?
No, no! The camera is back on Kobo again! Cute, right?
Stop stop stop stop stop stop! Mulai, mulai, mulai! Semua kamera diambil! Oke oke oke.
Stop, stop, stop! It's starting! You're taking all the camera time! Okay, okay.
Kalau gitu... Aduh, sampe kehabisan napas. Jangan berebutan di depan konser!
Alright then... Oh my, I'm out of breath. Don't fight over the camera!
Yeah! Iya iya iya! Kaela! Zeta! Iyes!
Yeah! Yes, yes! Kaela! Zeta! Yes!
Tapi...
But...
tapi iya ya udah deh.
but yeah, okay then.
Kalau enggak boleh rebutan komputer sama Zeta,
If we're not allowed to fight over the computer with Zeta,
hm... suka-suka aja ya, kita main aja deh sama penonton.
hm... whatever then, let me play with the audience.
Kobo pengin deh coba kita teriakin penonton karena kan tadi mereka sudah teriakin kita.
Kobo wants us to try shouting at the audience because they shouted at us earlier.
Iya, iya, iya.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Maksudnya kita teriakin untuk kita bareng penonton-penonton!
I mean, let's cheer together with the audience!
Betul!
That's right!
Teriaknya bareng penonton, jangan teriakin penontonnya.
Shout *with* the audience, don't shout *at* the audience.
Iya, gitu maksudnya!
Yeah, that's what I meant!
Soalnya kan habis ini kita harus nyanyi, jadi kita harus simpan suara dulu gak sih?
Because after this we have to sing, so shouldn't we save our voices first?
Betul ya.
True.
Tenang aja gak bakal selama durasi stream Kaela gitu ya guys ya.
Don't worry, it won't be as long as Kaela's stream duration, right guys?
Ya udah lah mau trek-trek ya udah, aku gak masalah dah, aku ngikut. Gimana nih semuanya? Udah siap belum?
Oh well, if you want to shout, go ahead, I don't mind. How about it everyone? Are you ready?
Siap gak?
Are you ready?
Siap nih kayaknya. Oke!
Looks like they're ready. Okay!
Kobo dulu ya!
Kobo first, okay!
Aku mau kita sama-sama teriak...
I want us to shout together...
Baka, baka, baka!
Oke, siap ya!
Okay, ready!
Satu, dua, tiga!
One, two, three!
Baka, baka, baka!
Suka, suka! Giliran Zeta, giliran Zeta!
Love it, love it! Zeta's turn, Zeta's turn!
Oke oke oke. Pas aku bilang "Mission: Start", kalian bareng-bareng teriak "Start" ya.
Okay okay okay. When I say "Mission: Start", you all shout "Start" together, okay?
Siap? Ah... Mission...
Ready? Ah... Mission...
Start!
Oke, habis ini Kaela.
Okay, next is Kaela.
Oke oke oke. Nah, ini ya buat semua penonton sama HoloHero juga.
Okay okay okay. Now, this is for all the audience and HoloHero too.
Kalau misalnya aku bilang "HoloHero!", kalian bilang "Hoo-hah!".
If I say "HoloHero!", you say "Hoo-hah!".
Gampang kan? Langsung langsung langsung.
Easy, right? Right away, right away!
Oke ya, siap ya.
Okay, ready?
HoloHero!
Hoo-hah!
Mantap, mantap!
Awesome, awesome!
Keren, keren, keren. Akhirnya GEN3 kompak juga.
Cool, cool, cool. Finally, Gen 3 is synced up too!
Iya, kompak. Kelihatannya masih pada semangat nih ya.
Yeah, synced up. Looks like everyone's still full of energy!
Soalnya dari lagu pertama kita hari ini aja udah kerasa banget.
Because even from our first song today, the energy was amazing.
Kalian tuh pada nyangka gak sih kalau lagu pertama kita tuh bakal 100%?
Did you guys expect that our first song would be 100%?
Beh, mana ada yang nyangka. Aku aja sendiri gak nyangka juga.
Man, who would've guessed? Even I didn't expect it myself.
Langsung dibuka dengan Hoshinova mode gitu, keren banget kan?
Opening right away in Hoshinova mode, super cool right?
Keren banget sih!
Super cool!
Keren banget sih, apalagi tadi Zeta sama Kaela nyanyi 100% tuh udah kayak real...
Super cool, especially earlier when Zeta and Kaela sang 100%, it felt like a real...
100%, ya. Itu tuh bisa gak sih...
100%, yeah. Could it be...
Gak sekeren tadi, aku tuh jadi ingin kayak... Kalian pernah kayak...
...not be that cool? It made me go like... Have you ever...
Kalian pernah gak sih nyanyi lagu sekeren tadi...
Have you ever sung a song as cool as that...
Aura farming-nya?
Aura farming?
Aura farming-nya sebetulnya keren banget, emang lagunya Moona.
The aura farming was actually super cool, it's Moona's song after all.
Emang kan Zeta kan soalnya biasanya lagu-lagu yang stylish, yang J-pop J-pop gitu.
Right, because Zeta usually sings stylish songs, like J-pop stuff.
Jadi tadi pas dinyanyiin tuh ya, 100%, rasanya jadi beda banget vibes-nya.
So when 100% was sung earlier, the vibes felt totally different.
Terus Kaela juga, tadi nge-rap yang "Su-tata tata tata", kayak apa tuh...
And Kaela too, rapping that "su-tata tata tata", like what was that...
Tata tata tata tata...
Iya, pokoknya keren banget!
Yeah, anyway it was so cool!
Keren banget ya tadi.
That was super cool earlier.
Tapi habis ini tuh masih ada lagi... "NEW ZOMBIE"!
But after this, there's still more... "NEW ZOMBIE"!
Ayo, pada tahu dong ini lagunya siapa?
Come on, you guys know whose song this is, right?
Tahu lah, tahu lah, senpai kita, senpai kita.
Of course, of course, our senpai, our senpai.
Tadi tuh itu ya, Holoro tuh perform-nya juga keren banget, kayak lagi di game gitu.
Earlier, Holoro's performance was super cool too, like being inside a game.
Betul, setuju! Terus tadi ada backdancer-nya main... keren ya guys! Keren gak?
True, agreed! And earlier the backup dancers were... cool right guys? Isn't it cool?
Betul! Ada apa lagi tuh tadi? Lampu laser, terus ada efek kembang api segala.
Right! What else was there? Laser lights, and fireworks effects too.
Terus banyak lah ya gimmick-gimmick yang wow. Tu backdancer nanti aku hire semua ya buat konser solo aku.
And so many wow gimmicks. I'll hire all those backup dancers for my solo concert later.
Wah, udah ngomong konser solo aja.
Wow, already talking about a solo concert.
Ya anggaplah doa ya.
Well, take it as a prayer.
Tapi konser yang ini belum selesai! Belum, belum, belum!
But *this* concert isn't over yet! Not yet, not yet, not yet!
Eh, tapi... kalian tahu gak sih sebelum ini tuh nyanyinya lagu apa?
Eh, but... do you guys know what song was sung before this?
Eh, aku mah tahu banget lah. Itu lagu terbaru aku. Dahlah.
Eh, of course I know. That's my newest song. "Dah lah".
Ya... udah lah? Gak usah dibahas? Dah lah...
Yeah... "udah lah" (forget it)? No need to discuss? Oh well...
Lho, kok gitu? Itu tuh maksudnya judulnya "Dallah", lagunya judulnya "Dallah"!
Wait, why like that? That means the title is "Dallah", the song's title is "Dallah"!
Oh! Iya, iya... Oh, Dallah!
Oh! Right, right... Oh, Dallah!
Bilang dong! Iya, habisnya kamu kan sering "dah lah, dah lah" gitu. Jadi dikira emang beneran "dah lah".
You should've said so! Well, because you often say "oh well, oh well", so we thought it really meant "whatever".
Entar "dalah, dalah", pulang dia.
Later if you say "dalah, dalah", she'll go home.
Kalau gitu "Dallah" tuh maksudnya apa sih?
If so, what does "Dallah" mean anyway?
"Dallah" sama kehidupan. Hidup tuh berat ya guys, ya. Kalau hidup berat ya udah "Dallah" aja, habis itu lanjutkan hidupmu, begitu.
"Dallah" with life. Life is tough, guys. If life is tough, just say "Dallah", then carry on with your life, like that.
Iya betul, teman-teman. Di kehidupan yang dewasa ini ya...
Yeah right, everyone. In this adult life...
Untung lagu-lagunya santai, easy listening.
Fortunately, the songs were chill and easy listening.
Jadi kita sambil keliling-keliling kan, nyapa fans kita ya?
So we could walk around while greeting our fans, right?
Asyik banget ya tadi ya? Aku juga suka banget tadi dance bagian chorus-nya ya.
That was so fun, right? I also really liked the dance during the chorus!
Da-la, da-la, da-la, da-la...
Itu beda lagu nggak, sih?
Isn't that a different song?
Da-la, da-la, da-la...
Nggak gitu deh. Nggak gitu kayaknya.
It wasn't like that. I don't think it was like that.
Iya, tapi pokoknya asyik lah ya kalau nyanyi...
Yeah, but anyway, it's fun singing...
...lagu chill, santai-santai kayak gini.
...chill, relaxed songs like this.
Iya, santai dong.
Yeah, relaxed of course.
Tapi ngomong-ngomong soal santai, kita tuh sebenarnya belum bisa santai dulu.
But talking about being relaxed, we actually can't relax just yet.
Hei, santai!
Hey, relax!
Karena katanya nggak boleh santai, terus...
Because they said we shouldn't relax, and...
Iya, jangan terlalu santai. Jangan terlalu santai.
Yeah, don't be too relaxed. Don't be too relaxed.
Karena konsernya tuh masih panjang!
Because the concert is still long!
Sebelum itu, kalian ada nggak yang mau kalian sampaikan dulu...
Before that, is there anything you want to say first...
...mulai dari ini nih, nggak bisa diam.
...starting from this one, who can't stay still?
Tiga kata saja.
Just three words.
I love you.
Keren, the best.
Cool, the best.
Sangat jelas, ya.
Very clear, indeed.
Tetap semangat, tetap semangat menjalani hidup, ya.
Stay enthusiastic, stay enthusiastic in going through life, okay?
Udah gitu aja. Pokoknya sampai akhir masih panjang, semangat!
That's it. Anyway, there's still a long way to the end, keep it up!
Saranghae-yo!
I love you!
Gomawo-yo!
Thank you!
Oke, kalau aku... ya... semangat selalu!
Okay, as for me... yeah... always stay energetic!
Semangat santai!
Relaxed energy!
Hidup jangan terlalu dibawa serius.
Don't take life too seriously.
Semangat santai, ya.
Relaxed energy, right?
Oke, kalau gitu kita lanjut...
Okay, if so, let's continue...
Eits, tunggu dulu! Sebelum selesai-selesai ini...
Hold on! Before ending this...
...kita teriak bareng-bareng penonton dulu, nggak sih?
...shouldn't we shout together with the audience first?
Iya dong! Ayo, ayo, ayo!
Yeah, of course! Come on, come on!
Oke, oke, jadi...
Okay, okay, so...
...kita teriak bareng ya, dalam hitungan tiga...
...we shout together, okay? On the count of three...
...kita sama-sama teriak "Chromatic Future", oke ya?
...let's all shout "Chromatic Future", okay?
Oke, oke! "Chromatic Future", gitu kan ya?
Okay, okay! "Chromatic Future", like that right?
Iya, kayak gitu, kayak gitu. Oke, langsung ya...
Yeah, like that, like that. Okay, right now...
...sambil lihat sini, sini, sini, sambil lihat.
...while looking over here, here, here, while looking.
Aku yang penonton ini nih, penonton yang ini.
I'll take this audience, this audience!
Aku yang ini deh, yang tengah, yang tengah. Halo!
I'll take this one, the middle, the middle. Hello!
Oke, bareng-bareng ya!
Okay, all together!
Satu, dua, tiga!
One, two, three!
Chromatic Future!
Everything was easy
I did it all alone
So effortlessly
I spread my wings and let my magic unfold
Got all problems solved
Without any setbacks
There is nothing uncontrolled
There's no way I can begin
Dream life that I need to win
I need to feel how all these things
Crumble into little pieces
I know I gotta soar a little higher
Hope all turns to be the things I desire
Layaknya burung merak yang bersayap
Like a peacock with its wings
'Kan kutaklukkan gelap
I'll conquer the darkness
Dengan sihir angin 'kan kuajak
Using my wind magic, I will invite
Semua yang terlelap 'tuk bangkit melawan dunia
All who are asleep to rise and fight against the world
We'll never give up
As long as we got the strength in ourselves
We could rise above the pain
We're stronger than them
Walking step by step
Trusting my own pace
Giving me what I deserve to have
Just believe me
They'll never bring me down
It'll never bring us down
Just believe me
Won't let their cruelty stealing my royalty
And when the universe works against me, I will just
Let it go
If it's spicy, just sip some tea
Let it go, let it go
Let it go
I've been living carefree
There's no bitter words in the world that could affect me
I spread my wings and let my magic unfold
Not letting it show
Stings, but I'm bigger than my feelings, so that'll be enough
There is no way I can begin
Dream life that I need to win
I need to feel how all these things
Crumble into little pieces
I know I gotta be better than ever
Hope all turns to be sweeter than ever
Layaknya burung merak yang bersayap
Like a peacock with its wings
'Kan kutaklukkan gelap
I'll conquer the darkness
Dengan sihir angin 'kan kuajak
Using my wind magic, I will invite
...mu yang terlelap 'tuk bangkit melawan dunia
...your dormant self to rise and fight against the world
We'll never give up!
As long as we got the strength in ourselves
We could rise above the pain
We're stronger than...
Walking step by step
Trusting by your pace
Giving me what I deserve to have
Let's go!
Just believe me, let it go
They'll never bring me down
It'll never bring us down
Just believe me
Won't let their cruelty steal my royalty
And when the universe was against me, I will just...
Let it go!
Come on guys, you know how to do this!
One, two, three, let it go!